亲爱的
Honey?
你记得给艾丽克斯
Did you remember to give Alex
和卢克午饭钱了吗
and Luke their lunch money?
记得 长官
Ma'am, yes, ma'am.
电工呢 你给他支票了吗
What about the electrician? Did you give him a check?
他是电工 他会给我们收费[充电]
He's an electrician -- he'll charge us.
我上班要迟到了 石基[喜剧演员]
I'm gonna be late for work, Shecky.
当然了 我付钱给他了
Yes, I paid him.
顺便说句 情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's, by the way.
不行
Mm, no.
跑完步都是汗 恶心死了
Gross and sweaty from running.
今晚的计划
So for later tonight,
你跟我想的一样吗 我的情人
You thinking what I'm thinking, Valentine?
我相信是一样的
I believe I am.
每次情人节
Every Valentine's day,
克莱尔和我都会玩点儿刺激的角色扮演
Claire and I look forward to some naughty role-playing --
性感狂野的奸夫淫妇朱莉安娜
sexually adventurous cuckolder Juliana
和克里夫·比克斯比
and Clive Bixby,
白天是扬声器推销员 晚上变身间谍
speaker salesman by day, spy by night.
同时也是情人
Lover also by night
有时候白天也是
and sometimes during the day.
扬声器生意 基本不用管
The speaker business, it -- it pretty much runs itself.
我希望今年非常低调
I just want to keep it really low-key this year.
简单就好
You know, simple.
行
Yep.
另一方面
On the other hand,
我们也可以去
we could have
我们喜欢的那家旅馆酒吧喝一杯
a drink at that hotel bar we love.
接着说
Go on.
然后直接回家
And come straight home...
穿上睡衣裤
Put on our Jammies,
看着电视渐渐入睡
and fall asleep in front of the TV.
完美
Perfect.
已经好期待了
Looking forward to it already.
但不要穿我讨厌的那些
Ew, but not those ones I hate,
红缎子睡衣
those red satin pajamas.
我都不知道那些在哪儿
I don't even know where those are.
我知道我会放下的
I know I'll get over it,
但现在我真的好讨厌安德斯和库珀
but right now I hate Anders and Cooper.
我们亲爱的朋友安德斯和库珀
Our dear friends Anders and Cooper
去年情人节结婚了
got married last Valentine's Day,
我们想送他们点特别的礼物
and we wanted to get them something really special.
我们找到了一副精美的小油画
We found this exquisite little painting...
画上是我们去年在纳帕
...of a winery in Napa
一起参观的一座酒庄
that we all visited last year.
有一点点...贵
It was a...bit pricey,
但他们很挑剔
but they're really judge-y
我们知道他们一定会喜欢的
and we knew they'd love it.
问题是 我们也喜欢
The problem is, so did we.
谢谢 卡尔梅利纳
Thank you, Carmelina.
这里有个礼物麻烦你
Oh, and here's s-something you can...
放到其他房间
put in the other room.
-好艰难 -太艰难了
- That was hard. - So hard.
也许莉莉的亲生母亲当初也是这感觉
Probably how Lily's birth mother felt.
但是我们可没有
Except we don't have nine
另外五位画家画的九幅油画
other paintings by five different painters.
天呐 米奇 小卡
Oh, my God. Mitch, Cam.
天呐 我们来早了吗
Oh, God, are we early?
-这可不是我们的风格 -很抱歉
- This is so not like us. - I'm sorry.
不不不 派对已经取消了
No, no, no. The party's been canceled.
-为什么 -库珀把我甩了
- Why? - Cooper's left me.
他正在申请离婚
He's filing for divorce.
我们结束了
The marriage is over!
-安德斯 -安德斯
- Ohh, Anders. - Anders.
我还以为我们是相爱的
I thought we were in love.
你以为你了解睡在隔壁房间的那个人
You think you know the person sleeping in the next bedroom.
我去给你们拿点酒
I'll get us some drinks.
好可怜
So sad.
是啊 也不一定
Yeah, it doesn't have to be.
如果是真爱
If it's really love,
你就要尽一切可能争取回
you do everything you need to do to get back
你曾经拥有的一切
what you once had.
你在说那幅画吧
You're talking about the painting, right?
当然了 因为我们不欠他什么了
Of course I am 'cause we don't owe him that anymore.
-去拿吧 -好了
- Go get it! - Okay.
快去拿
Go get it.
你今天一定有什么重大计划吧
You must have big plans today.
这节日简直就是你的超级碗大赛
This is like your Super Bowl, right?
今年我不打算采取行动
I'm sitting it out this year.
这个节日已经商业化到可笑的地步了
The whole holiday's gotten laughably commercial.
看来你被艾米拒绝了
Sounds like Amy turned you down.
就像豪华酒店的床一样
Like a bed in a five-star hotel.
我要慢慢地在
I'll be drowning my sorrows
我的新欢罪案剧中忘掉我的悲伤
in a marathon of my new favorite true-crime show,
《致命女士》
"Lethal Ladies."
艾米也许是甩了我
Amy may have dumped me,
但至少不是从嘉年华游轮的甲板上
but at least it wasn't off the lido deck
把我的尸体甩出去
of a Carnival Cruise.
我知道 桑娅
I know, Sonia.
瞧瞧谁回来了 桑格利亚姐妹花
Look who's back -- the Sangria sisters.
我邀请我妹妹来作客
I invited my sister to visit
好解决我们之间的矛盾
so that we could fix our problems.
你懂的 姐妹间的小摩擦
You know, sister things,
比如我很讨厌她总是借我的梳子
like I never liked how she always borrowed my brush,
而她也很讨厌
or she never liked
我抢了她离开小村庄的机会
how I stole her one chance to escape the village
而把她留在那里 照顾我母亲
and I left her there, taking care of my mother.
类似的事情
Things like that.
杰 桑娅的航班延误到了明天
Jay, they delayed Sonia's flight until tomorrow.
我们何不取消晚餐预订
Why don't we cancel our dinner reservation
我们三个一起在家里庆祝情人节
and the three of us celebrate Valentine's here?
你不用为了我这么做 歌洛莉亚
You don't have to do that for me, Gloria.
情人节我通常都在
I usually spend Valentine's Day
村子那口井附近卖手工花
selling artificial flowers near the well in my village.
你们都住哪儿啊 《国家地理》杂志吗
Where do you people live, National Geographic?
这样我会很内疚
I just feel so bad.
你们这星期对我这么好
You have both shown me such kindness this week,
我却只给你们带来坏天气
and I repay you with bad weather over Tampa.
不会 这样更好
No, this is better.
外面过节的人太多了
It gets crazy out there.
能避开那些纷扰我很开心
I'm happy to avoid the fuss.
有点纷扰也不错
Wouldn't have minded a little fuss.
我感觉最近有点被忽视了
Maybe I've been kind of feeling taken for granted lately.
我知道只有小姑娘
I know only girls are
才会在乎什么情人节 但是
supposed to care about Valentine's day, but --
我在哀嚎什么啊
Ah, what am I crying about?
我们赚的钱多 管它呢
We get paid more, so what the hell?
库珀做人太不地道了
Cooper didn't even have the decency
都没给我时间取消派对厨师预约
to leave me in time to cancel the caterer.
如果你有胃口 这有三百只芥末大虾
I have 300 of this wasabi shrimp if you're hungry.
不用了 谢谢
Oh, no, thank you.
沙丁鱼肉酱 橄榄脆吐司
Sardine rillettes, olive crostini --
要怎么才能吃完啊
What am I supposed to do with all of this?
卡尔梅利纳 那是给客人吃的
Carmelina, that's for company.
小卡来了 我们该走了
Oh, well, there's Cam, so we should probably go.
你离开了好久 我还担心你吵醒了我妈
Oh, you were gone so long, I was afraid you'd woken mother.
妈妈
Uh, m-mother?
我没提到吗
Didn't I mention?
她在这里康复 刚置换了两个髋关节
She's recuperating here, just had both hips replaced.
那提醒了我
Oh, that reminds me --
我该把摄像头安在她房间里
I should put on the security camera in her room.
-你拿到了吗 -拿到了
- Did you get it? - Yes.
猜猜他们把最后送来的结婚礼物放在哪里
And guess where they keep the last-minute wedding gifts?
提示一下 显然你需要原来的髋关节
Hint -- apparently you need your original hips
才能让睡衣合上
to keep a nightgown closed.
很高兴你们过来了
Well, I'm glad you stopped by.
我真的很需要
I really needed this.
小卡 来吧
Oh, Cam, get in here.
我有点鼻塞
Oh, I have a little bit of a sniffle.
来吧
Oh, come on.
这是什么
What's this?
那是...
Uh, that is, um --
送给你和库珀的结婚礼物
That's a wedding gift for you and Cooper,
但我们听说后 就觉得这不合适
but once we heard, we didn't think it was appropriate.
你开玩笑吗
Oh, are you kidding?
收礼物就没有不合适的时候
There's no bad time for a gift.
抱歉 我们送得太晚了
I'm -- I'm sorry it's so late.
我们只是想送你
We just wanted to get you something
你会珍爱的东西
that you would really cherish.
这是我们送出的最棒的礼物
Pretty much the best gift we've ever given anyone.
是啊 这是很漂亮的...
Yeah, it's -- it's a beautiful...
奶酪盘
Cheese plate!
是的 看到这异想天开的措辞
Yes, I got that from the...
我就知道了
whimsical phrasing.
你们确定不留下再喝一杯吗
Are you sure you won't stay for one more,
特别是现在我有了这个
especially now since I've got this
时髦的传送奶酪的系统
stylish cheese-delivery system?
-就一杯 -真棒
- Just one, yeah. - Great.
怎么回事
What happened?!
显然有两个包装得很像的礼物
Obviously there were two gifts wrapped similarly,
而我的眼睛里含着泪水
and my eyes were watering
因为那房间里充斥着药膏味道
from the thick fog of Vaporub back there.
反正我们现在无所畏惧了
Okay, well, we got nothing to lose now,
回去拿那幅画
so go back and get the painting.
你知道谁送了他那个便宜的东西吗
You know who gave him that cheap thing?
杰玛库斯 她赚的第一块钱都还在呢
J'marcus. She's got the first dollar she ever earned --
快去吧
Just go!
桑娅毁了我的情人节之后
Once Sonia blew up my Valentine's Day,
我本可以坐着为自己感到难过
I could have sat around feeling sorry for myself.
但我轻笑了一会儿
Instead, I had a little chuckle,
然后给狗狗买了礼物
and I got the dog a gift.
我知道这很愚蠢 给斯黛拉买礼物
I know it's silly getting Stella a present...
她的生日快到了
So close to her birthday.
她在吗
Is she around?
我觉得她在楼上的浴室里
I think she's upstairs in the bath.
什么 我今早刚给她洗过澡
What? I just gave her a bath this morning.
你说的是斯黛拉
Oh, you're talking about Stella.
等等 你给狗狗买了礼物吗
Wait, you got the dog a gift?
你没资格评判我
Lot of attitude
你的约会对象是一桶冰淇淋
for a guy whose date's a tub of
和一条毛绒绒的睡袍
ice cream and a fuzzy robe.
你简直就像《凯西》漫画里的主人公
You're spending Valentine's Day in a "Cathy" cartoon.
这是干什么
Hey, what's all this?
我还以为我们三个
I thought the three of us
就叫点外卖呢
were just gonna order something in.
不 我已经毁了你们的夜晚
No. I ruined your night enough.
我要给你和歌洛莉亚做饭
I'm cooking for you and Gloria
好让你们独自度过浪漫的夜晚
so you can have a romantic evening alone.
桑娅 你没必要这样做
Sonia, you don't have to do this.
我想这样
I want to.
为你们准备食物我觉得很开心
It makes me so happy to prepare food for you.
也许以后我也会给自己的老公做饭
Maybe someday I'll be preparing it for a husband of my own.
谢谢你没有笑到在地上打滚
Thank you for not laughing and falling on the floor
我说这种话时我妈妈就会那样做
like my mother does when I say such things.
今天是情人节 我...
You know, it being Valentine's Day and all, I, uh --
我给你准备了点东西
I got you a little something.
有要洗的衣服吗
Ooh, laundry?
不
No.
给你
Here.
不行
I can't.
来吧 打开
Come on! Open it.
瞧见这个"S"了吗
Here, see that "S" there?
代表桑娅
That's for "Sonia."
杰 好漂亮
Oh, Jay, it's so beautiful.
我不知道该怎么...
I don't know what to...
谢谢你
Thank you!
我什么时候会学到教训
When will I learn?
我太吸引小姨子了
I'm catnip to sister-in-laws.
多年前 感恩节晚餐时 我坐在迪迪的姐姐
Years ago, I was sitting next to Dede's sister Cece
西西旁边
at Thanksgiving dinner,
我对她施展了一些魅力
and I threw a little charm her way.
眨了眨蓝眼睛
You know, flash the baby blues.
我还没反应过来
And before I know it,
她就用12码的脚在我的胫骨上摩擦了
she's rubbing her size 12s up and down my shin.
迪迪发现了
Dede caught her,
走去桌子那边跟她打了起来
went over the table at her.
靠她姐碧碧和我才把她俩分开
It took me and her sister Bebe to separate them.
你在哪里
Hey, where are you?
我都给你打了15分钟的电话了
I've been trying you for 15 minutes.
我知道 会议延迟了
I know. We ran late.
然后车又没法发动
And then the car wouldn't start,
我不得不打给汽车协会
so I had to call AAA.
他们说在来的路上了 但谁知道呢
They said they're on their way, but who knows?
我急得满脸冒油
I'm all greasy.
亲爱的 我觉得我没法过去了
Oh, honey, I don't think I'm gonna make it.
别生气
Don't be mad.
我很生气
I am mad.
你本该20分钟前到的
You were supposed to be here 20 minutes ago.
这是我们为我俩留出的一夜
This is the one night we set aside for us.
我知道 我觉得很糟糕
I know, and I feel terrible,
但是听着 喝完酒 回家去
but listen, finish your drink, come on home.
也许我们可以过个浪漫的复活节
Maybe we'll have a romantic Easter.
买单
Check, please.
我听说你妻子的车出了故障
I understand that your wife has had some car trouble.
那是怎么回事啊
I wonder how that could have happened?
我必须说 朱莉安娜
I must say, Juliana,
我今晚绝对没想到会在这里见到你
you're the last person I expected to see here tonight.
如果走运的话
Well, with any luck,
你今晚会是我看到的最后一个人
you'll be the last person I do see tonight.
天啊
Oh, my God.
菲尔 我注意你好几年了
Phil, I've had my eye on you for years.
我很高兴
I'm just so happy
我们终于能独处一段时间了
we're finally gonna get some alone time.
我没吓到你吧
I'm not scaring you, am I?
恰恰相反
Quite the contrary.
大部分见到我的女人
Most women who meet me
立刻就要求跟我独处
almost instantly ask for some alone time.
抱歉
Excuse me.
该死
Darn it!
我带客户看房的事提前到明早了
My showing was pushed up tomorrow morning.
我也许得早点回去
I-I may have to make it an early one.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
因为你跟我只有一晚上的时间 猛虎
'Cause you only have one night with me, tiger,
而我就和
and I'm as flexible
政府担保的零首付
as a government-insured, zero-down,
浮息按揭一样灵活
variable-rate mortgage.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
不如我们离开这里怎么样
What do you say we get out of here?
-你在干什么 -跑 快跑
- What are you doing? - Run, run!
可这瓶酒还没付钱呢
But we haven't even paid for this.
我们是法外狂徒 宝贝 快跑
We're outlaws, baby. Go, go!
刚才可真是太刺激了
That was such a rush!
你以前从没偷过什么东西吧
You've never stolen anything before?
我只在高中时
Only the entire show
偷了整场《绿野仙踪》表演的风头
of my high-school production of "The wiz,"
不过我认为那不算是...
but I don't think that's --
观光电梯 可以看到绝美的风景了
Oh, glass elevator. Should make for an exciting view.
是街上的行人会看到绝美的风景了
It will for the people on the street.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我根本没听见他们上来了
I didn't even hear them get on.
也许你该掏耳朵了
Well, maybe it's time for an ear cleaning.
不用了 你刚才把它们冲得很干净了
I don't know, you just sluiced them out pretty good.
我觉得有点热 菲尔
I'm getting kind of hot, Phil.
你说我们去凉快一下怎么样
What do you say we cool off a bit?
这主意简直太棒了 朱莉安娜
Aw, that would have been great, Juliana.
可惜已经天黑了
Too bad it's after...dark.
女巫
Sorceress.
你说得对 朱莉安娜
You were right, Juliana.
这清凉的晚风正是我们所需要的
This cool night air is just the thing.
这位女士需要我的外套吗
Would the lady like my coat
这样就不会感冒...
so she doesn't catch a col--
跟我想的是一样的吗
Does that mean what I think it does?
水有点凉
Water's a little chilly.
你能不能下来帮我暖和一下
Think you can come in here and help me warm it up?
宝贝 还没有我温暖不了的泳池
Baby, they haven't built a pool I couldn't warm a little.
-小卡呢 -又去厕所了
- Where's Cam? - Uh, tinkling again.
大自然召唤得太勤了
Nature calls so often,
可能把他列入快速拨号了
I think she has him on speed dial.
那是什么
Oh, what's that?
我母亲房里的运动检测器警报
The motion-detector alarm in mother's room
为防止她从床上掉下来
in case she falls out of bed.
酒会的时候我把它打开了
I turn it on during cocktails,
害怕自己会忘记她还在那里
when I tend to forget she's even there.
怎么了 她没事吧
What's going on? She all right?
没事 没事 只是在晃腿
Yeah, yeah, she's just tossing her leg a little bit.
又踢腿了吗
Oh, that kicky thing?
她要么是在做梦跳火箭女郎舞
She's either having her rockettes dream
要么就是她的导尿管掉了
or her catheter's out.
她没事
She's fine.
冰块没有了
Oh, we're out of ice!
噩梦不断啊
The nightmare continues!
老天
God.
我找到了
Hey, I got it.
好 快放回去
Okay, put it back.
我一定是听错了吧
I can't possibly have heard you correctly.
那里有个装着圣安杰洛牌玻璃碗的盒子
There is a box over there with a Santangelo glass bowl
是他们准备送我们的结婚礼物
that they got us for our wedding.
一会就说那个奶酪盘只是个笑话
We'll just say that the cheese plate was a little joke
真正的礼物在另一个房间里
and that the real present is in the other room.
快去
Hurry!
对了 你们今天来
You know, your coming around today
让我想起库珀和我为你们准备了结婚礼物
reminded me that Cooper and I got you a wedding gift.
是吗
You did?
真是太让我惊喜了
Well, now, this is a surprise.
尽管上面没有标明
Well, even though it doesn't say so on it,
是条鱼 恭喜你们
it's a fish! Congrats.
天呐 塑料的橄榄剑
Oh, my god! Plastic olive swords?
卡尔梅利纳 你是想被驱逐出境吗
Carmelina, are you trying to be deported?!
好了 放回去了
All right, I got it back.
那是什么
What is that?
是安德斯给我们的结婚礼物
This is Anders' wedding present to us.
他一定是看到我们送他的
He must have swapped it out
那个畸形的东西后把礼物换掉了
when he opened that monstrosity that he thinks we got him.
我们得把画拿回来
We're getting our painting back.
-快去 -我吗
- Go. - Me?
不不 你已经侦察过那个房间了
No, no. You've already done a recon of the room.
你去做
You need to do this.
放轻松 "碟中谍"
Okay, take it easy, "Mission impossible."
那里只有一张床和一个沙发 不是迷宫
It's a bed and a couch, not a laser maze.
快去吧
Now get.
喝点香槟酒 晚饭十分钟就好
A little champagne, and dinner will be ready in 10 minutes.
谢谢
Ay, gracias!
杰 谢谢你给我买的新手镯
Oh, Jay, thank you so much for my new bracelet.
你真是太客气了
You shouldn't have.
说到首饰和"太客气"
And speaking of jewlry and "shouldn't haves,"
我觉得有点对不起桑娅
I was feeling sorry for Sonia,
我给了她一个小玩意
and I gave her a little trinket.
你真好
Oh, that's so sweet.
是 但那个可怜的姑娘对我太热情了
Yeah, but now the poor kid's got the hots for me.
我不知道这是为什么
I don't know what it is.
也许我只是不了解自己的魅力所在
Maybe I just don't know my own power.
你一定时常会感觉到吧
I mean, you must get that sometimes.
不要生气啊
Don't be mad.
也不要这样笑 不管是为什么
And don't be whatever that is, either.
她抱着我不肯松手
She hugged me and wouldn't let go.
不是我瞎想
It's not that crazy.
这事以前也发生过
This has happened before.
是啊 迪迪的
Oh, yeah, that time
独居妹妹抱着你腿不放的那次
when Dede's lonely sister grabbed your leg?
不是独居 她是护林员
Not lonely. She's a forest ranger.
她根本冷静不下来
She can't be tied down.
在我回去之前
Look, before I shuffle back to my bell tower,
我想说 我知道那种表情
let me just say I know the look.
杰 拜托
Ay, Jay, please.
真对不起
I'm so sorry
今天没怎么好好关心你
that I didn't pay attention to you at all today.
你现在都开始胡思乱想了
And now you're all crazy.
歌洛莉亚 我找不到蜡烛台了
Gloria, I can't find the candlesticks!
别担心 我来帮你
Ay, don't worry. I go help you!
歌洛莉亚 你没事吧
Gloria, are you all right?
我的脚踝
My ankle!
乔的玩具怎么会在这里
Why is Joe's toy here?
天呐 你扭到脚了是不是
Oh, gee, you really twisted it, huh?
没事 亲爱的 我去给你拿冰敷一下
All right, honey. Let me get some ice on that.
我听到有人摔倒了 没事吧
I heard a crash. Is everything okay?
是啊 歌洛莉亚扭到脚了
Yeah, Gloria turned her ankle.
我不知道她还能不能下来吃晚饭了
I don't know if she's gonna make it down for dinner.
不
Oh, no!
要我把食物拿到楼上去吗
Should I bring your food upstairs?
不用 她想休息一下
No, she just wants to rest.
她让我跟你在楼下吃
She told me to eat with you downstairs.
她不想制造什么...
She doesn't want to make any --
麻烦
...trouble.
那是我有生以来最刺激的一夜
That was the most exciting night of my life.
要是我鼓掌的话会不会破坏气氛
Would it break the mood if I clapped a little?
不会 我可以允许
No, I will allow it.
瞧瞧 这里提供高档的棉签
Ooh, look, they have the good q-tips.
我要偷一把回去
I'm gonna steal us a bunch.
我会想念朱莉安娜的
I'm gonna miss Juliana.
那女人真是无所不知无所不能
That lady knows where the bodies are buried.
谢谢 亲爱的
Oh, thanks, honey.
我知道前几年的情人节我都不是很上心
I know some years I miss the mark on Valentine's Day.
但今年 我想要确保...
This year, I wanted to make sure --
她真是富有冒险精神又让人惊喜
She's just so adventurous and surprising.
就像在我口渴得要命时
It's like I was parched,
她用一大杯惊喜之酒来为我解渴
and she quenched my thirst with a big goblet of "Wow."
我们得确保在下次斟满之前
Well, we'll have to make sure your goblet doesn't get so low
你酒杯里的酒不会变得太少
before we fill her up again.
我没听懂你的意思 但不管怎样
I don't know what that means, but anyway,
我想要不我们回家吧
I'm kind of thinking maybe we'll just go home.
明早我真的要带客户看房
That showing really is early,
我得早点休息
and I need to be sharp.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我以为你想在这里睡
I thought you wanted to sleep here.
是啊 当时太沉浸于
Yeah, I got caught up
与朱莉安娜的欢愉之中了
in the whole Juliana moment.
可以帮我看看有没有针线包吗
Hey, would you see if there's any sewing kits?
家里好像没有了
I think we're out.
好
Yeah.
有什么地方不对劲
Something was off,
但我不太确定是什么
but I couldn't quite put my finger on it.
克莱尔 我们走吧
Claire, let's get a move on!
来了 来了 稍等
I'm coming. I'm coming. Hang on.
瞧瞧谁回来了
Well, look who's back.
是啊 我本来要换衣服的
Yeah, well, I would have changed,
但我只带了这身
but this is all I brought.
换衣服做什么 你穿这身多完美
Change? When you're perfect?
嘴真甜
Oh, that's so nice.
天呐 看看
Oh, my, god, look at that.
都这么晚了 是吧
It really has gotten late, hasn't it?
对于你这种
Not for a lady
属于夜晚的女士来说不算晚 朱莉安娜
of the evening like yourself, Juliana.
我们再去观光电梯里亲热一番
What's say we fog up that glass elevator again
再到酒吧喝一杯怎么样
and grab a nightcap in the bar?
然后我知道是什么不对劲了
Then I put my finger on it --
我丈夫爱上了另一个女人
My husband's in love with another woman.
-你很爱吃 是吧 -是啊
- You like that, don't you? - Mmm, yeah.
歌洛莉亚真可怜 是吧
Poor Gloria, though, huh?
她会没事的
She'll be fine.
你嘴上沾了点东西
Oh, you have a little something --
这回我自己擦吧
Oh, I'll get it this time.
抱歉
Oh, excuse me.
汤好了 我给歌洛莉亚端上去一点
Oh, the soup is ready. I'll bring some for Gloria.
不是我胡思乱想吧
I'm not crazy, right?
不是 她看上你了
No. She's into you.
谢天谢地你下来了
Thank god you wandered down here when you did.
你看到她总是靠近我了吧
You see how she keeps sliding close to me?
就像在船上吃饭一样
It's like eating on a boat.
比那更糟
It's so much worse than that.
简直和《致命女士》的剧情一样
It's straight out of "Lethal Ladies."
看我在垃圾桶里找到了什么
Look what I found in the trash.
我们的合照 歌洛莉亚的头被剪掉了
Pictures of me and Gloria with Gloria's head cut out?
她就是想除掉妈妈
She literally wants mom out of the picture.
等等
Hold on, amigo.
她迷上我了吗 是的
- Is she infatuated with me? Yes.
完全可以理解 无可避免
Understandable, unavoidable.
但她真的会对自己的亲...
But would she actually do something to her own --
怎么了
What?!
她刚刚从包里拿出一个瓶子
She just took a bottle out of her purse
往妈妈的汤里撒了点东西
and sprinkled it into mom's soup.
行了 你罪案剧看得太多了
Okay, that's enough of this dumb TV show for you.
现在说的是一种完全可信的迷恋
We're talking about a perfectly believable obsession.
你是在把这事编造成一种...
You're trying to make this into something that's --
给 曼尼
Here, Manny.
给我的吗 那杰呢
That's for me? What about Jay?
太辣了 他喝不了
Oh, it's too spicy for him.
我会给你妈妈弄一碗和这碗一样的
I make another one just like yours for your mother.
趁热喝了吧
Eat it while it's hot. Okay.
天呐
Oh, my god.
她也想除掉我
She wants me out of the picture, too.
当然了
Of course.
年轻女人遇到个富有的老男人
Young woman meets a wealthy, older man.
谁愿带个碍事的孩子呢
Who wants a kid in the way?
这是你今天说的第一句符合逻辑的话
That's the first airtight thing you've said today.
但她不是谋杀犯
But she's not a murderer
斯黛拉 别喝
Stella, no!
真感人 你倒是愿意让我喝毒药
Oh, that's nice. You'd let me eat the soup.
快弄干净
Just clean it up.
睁开眼看看吧 杰
Open your eyes, Jay.
她想要据你为己有
She wants you all to herself.
穿着像妈妈那样的红裙子
The red dress just like mom's,
害妈妈踩到玩具摔倒
the toy she knew mom would trip on,
把照片里妈妈的头剪掉
the headless pictures?
她是个疯子
She's crazy!
你觉得我是疯子吗
You think I'm crazy?
这是我用剪下来的头像做的
This is what I did with the pictures.
我为歌洛莉亚做了这张情人节卡片
I made this Valentine for Gloria.
我向歌洛莉亚借了这条裙子
The dress I borrowed from Gloria
搭配你送我的项链
to go with your pretty necklace.
而那瓶"毒药"是香料
And the "Poison" is guasca,
是我从哥伦比亚带来的
a spice I brought from Colombia.
那个玩具是斯黛拉经常玩的
And there's Stella with the toy.
她总是把玩具弄得到处都是
Which she leaves all over the house.
这之中有些误会
There's been some misunderstanding here,
但如果你可以
but it would be so super
不要告诉别人的话就太好了
if you just wouldn't mention this to --
不告诉我吗
Me?!
她俩嗓门这么大 走路倒是没声音
As loud as these two are, the move like cats.
我在婴儿监听器里都听到了
I heard everything on the baby monitor.
你怎么能那样说我的妹妹
How can you say these things about my sister?
我只是想表示友善 杰
I was just trying to be nice, Jay.
我会叫辆出租车 去机场等我的航班
I will call a cab and wait at the airport.
现在我知道你们一家人怎么看我了
Now I know what your family really thinks of me.
桑娅 等等
Sonia, wait!
一周来我努力化解我和桑娅
I have been working on fixing my relationship with Sonia
之间的矛盾
the whole week,
结果因为你以为自己是性感机器
and because you think you're a sex machine,
你把一切都毁了
you have ruined everything.
抱歉 我去和她谈谈
I'm sorry. I'll talk to her.
桑娅 我真是太傻了
Sonia, I'm an idiot.
我今天乱下结论
I jumped to some crazy conclusions today.
也许是因为情人节的缘故
I mean, I could say it's because of Valentine's
或是 我不知道
or, I don't know,
我感觉自己有点被忽视了
me feeling a little neglected,
但我知道你绝对不会
but I know you could never --
吻我
Kiss me.
是的 因为你是我的小姨子
Yes, because you're my sister-in-law and, uh --
我们隐藏得很完美 杰
We hid it perfectly, Jay!
桑娅 等等
Sonia, wait!
我们已经等得够久了
We've waited long enough!
与我共度一晚 你就会忘了她
One night with me, and you'll forget all about her.
她不欣赏你
She doesn't appreciate you.
我听到过你们吵架
I hear how you fight!
我们就那样聊天
That's just how we talk.
放弃吧 杰 我们都
Give in to it, Jay. We both--
不
Oh, no.
我就知道
I knew it!
你居然想把我从你那偷来的好日子
How dare do you try to steal the life
再偷回去
that I stole from you?!
放手吧 歌洛莉亚 我爱他
Let him go, Gloria! I love him!
永不放手
Never!
他是我丈夫 我更爱他
He's my husband, and I love him more!
女士们 别闹了
Ladies, ladies, stop.
你是谁
W-who are you?
我 我是你儿子的朋友
I-I-I'm a friend of you son's.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
我扭到脖子了 我需要枕头
I twisted my neck, and I need my pillow.
我很难受
I'm in agony.
老妈搬进来确实不方便
Yes, mother moving in was inconvenient,
但要我怎么做 就这么不管她吗
but what did he want me to do, just get rid of her?
谁会干那种事啊
Who does that?
魔鬼才会那么干
I mean, a ghoul, that's who.
-哦不 -怎么了
- Oh, no! - What's wrong?
没什么 我只是在重温
Nothing. I was just reliving the moment
你说你和库珀分手了的那一刻
you told us about you and Cooper.
你太贴心了
You're so dear.
其实 我给你和米奇尔的那条鱼
You know that, that fish I gave you and Mitchell?
那不是我们给你们选的礼物
That really wasn't the gift we picked out for you.
-真的吗 -我只是故意整你们的
- Really? - No, I was just being mean.
只是当我看到那个奶酪盘的时候 我
It's just that, when I saw that cheese plate, I just --
等等
Wait a minute. Did--
你们送那个给我们是因为库珀和我
did you give us that because Cooper and I
提起过要开个奶酪店吗
talked about opening up a little cheese shop?
是啊 不然呢
Yes! Why else?
太贴心了
How sweet!
卡尔梅利纳可能都要到家了
Carmelina's probably halfway home with it,
但我可以叫她拿回来
but I can make her walk back.
这个
And this...
这是给你们的
This is for you.
我们很为你们高兴
We really were so happy for you.
安德斯
Oh, Anders.
我们该走了 不过看看是谁起床了
Well, we should probably get going, but look who is up.
妈妈 你的帽子呢
Mother, where's your hat?
安德斯最终还是把碗送给我们了
Look, Anders gave us the bowl after all.
你拿不到画也没关系
It's a good thing you couldn't get the painting.
我们不能现在把它拿走
We couldn't take it now.
好好用这个碗
Well, enjoy the bowl.
你们也该在家里摆点像样的东西了
It's about time you boys had something pretty in the house.
你没事
Oh, you're fine.
我爱你
I love you.
当你丈夫注意到另一个女人
Your husband's noticing another woman,
你要做的只有一件事
there's only one thing to do --
再接再厉
step up your game.
我迫不及待地想要泡个热水澡
I just can't wait to get in a hot bath
泡泡我感染了的脚趾甲
and soak this infected toenail.
诋毁另一个女人就完事了
It's much easier just to take the other bitch down.
我喜欢这个主意
Well, I-I like the sound of that bath.
浴缸四周会点满香薰蜡烛吧
I assume the tub will be ringed with scented candles?
我当然有蜡烛了 我蜡烛多着呢
Oh, well, I've got candles. I got candles everywhere.
自从我男朋友不再付我的账单
Ever since my boyfriend stopped paying my bills,
他们就掐掉了我的电
they turned off the electricity.
这让我们能够制造自己的电流
Leaving us to generate our own electricity.
其实蜡烛会非常助兴
Although, candles can be nice
要是你想来一段"辣身舞"的话
if you're in the mood for, say, some Dirty Dancing.
我讨厌那部电影
Oh, I hate that movie.
什么
What?!
我不得不说我非常不同意
There I must passionately disagree.
还是说你故意来这招的
Or was that your game all along?
既然你想争 那就争吧
Okay, if it's an argument you want, fine.
来吧
Fine!
强尼当然会爱上芭比
Of course Johnny's gonna fall for Baby
因为他就是个乡巴佬
because he's this big, dreamy country bumpkin
而她美丽又年轻
and she is the shiny, new thing.
但电影结束后
But what happens when the movie is over,
当他真正了解她后 会发生什么
when he really gets to know her?
在卡茨基尔待上两周 他就会说
Two weeks out of the Catskills, and it's,
你又穿这衣服了 芭比
"You wearing that again, Baby?
你又借我的剃须刀了 芭比
You borrow my razor again, Baby?
两杯酒还不够多吗 芭比
Isn't two glasses enough, Baby?"
相信我 他再也不是在享受人生了
Trust me, he is no longer having the time of his life.
朱莉安娜
Juliana.
-朱莉安娜 等等 -不
- Juliana, wait. - No.
菲尔 还差一分钟就十二点了
Honestly, it is one minute to 12:00, Phil.
情人节已经结束了
Valentine's Day is over.
还没有
Not quite.
我再也不能见你了
I can't see you anymore.
什么
What?
不敢相信我要说这些
I can't believe I'm saying this
因为你是一个男人这辈子能遇到的
because you're the most intoxicating woman
最致命的诱惑
a man could ever meet.
但是 不知道被什么迷了心窍
But, by some cosmic miracle,
那座房子里有个女人
there's a woman in that house
我仍然像初遇时一样
I still find as sexy and exciting
觉得她性感又让人振奋
as the first day I met her.
我应该更经常让她知道这点
I should probably let her know that more often than I do.
是我的错
That's my bad.
但重点是
But, point is,
如果一个男人能找到这么好的老婆
a guy like me gets that lucky,
他会及时回头
he quits while he's ahead.
我觉得她才是幸运的那个
It sounds to me like she's the lucky one.
再见 朱莉安娜
Goodbye, Juliana.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
抱歉 我们难道不是要
Sorry. Aren't -- aren't we --
别求我
Don’t, don't beg.
有点尊严吧
It's beneath you.
但我
But I --
走吧 我妻子会看见你的
Please, go. My wife will see you.
走 走去哪里
Go? Go where?
别让我更不忍心了
Don't make this harder than it is.
好吧
Okay.
朱莉安娜 不
Juliana, no.
菲尔
Phil!
来真的吗
Really?!
我不知道你怎么还这么开心
You know, I don't know why you are so happy.
我已经试着把圣安杰洛碗
I've tried the Santangelo
放在六个不同的地方了
in six different places.
只让我越发觉得
And it just make me
这个家的每个细节都让人不能忍受
hate everything in our house.
搬家
We're moving.